<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Reversi</string>
    <string name="white_turn">White Turn</string>
    <string name="black_turn">Black Turn</string>
    <string name="available_moves">Available moves - </string>
    <string name="no_moves_available">No moves available!</string>
    <string name="current_score">Score - </string>

    <string name="html">
        <![CDATA[

        <string name="html">

        </br>
        <h2>History</h2>
        <p>
        The game <b>Reversi</b> was invented in 1883 by either of two Englishmen (each claiming the other
        a fraud), Lewis Waterman or John W. Mollett (or perhaps earlier by someone else entirely),
         and gained considerable popularity in England at the end of the nineteenth century.The
         game\'s first reliable mention is in the August twenty-first 1886 edition of The Saturday
         Review. Later mention includes an 1895 article in The New York Times: "Reversi is something
          like Go Bang, and is played with 64 pieces.\" In 1893, the well-known German games
          publisher Ravensburger started producing the game as one of its first titles.
          Two 18th-century continental European books dealing with a game that may or may not
          be Reversi are mentioned on page fourteen of the Spring 1989 Othello Quarterly, and there
          has been speculation, so far without documentation, that the game has even more ancient origins.
        </p></br>

        <h2>Rules</h2>

        <p>Each of the disks\' two sides corresponds to one player; they are referred to here as
        <b>light</b> and <b>dark</b> after the sides of Othello pieces, but any counters with distinctive
        faces are suitable. The game may for example be played with a chessboard and Scrabble pieces,
        with one player letters and the other backs.</p>

        <p>
        The historical version of Reversi starts with an empty board, and the first two moves
        by each player are in the four central squares of the board. The players place their disks
         alternately with their color facing up and no captures are made. A player may choose to
          not play both pieces on the same diagonal, different from the standard Othello opening.
          It is also possible to play variants of Reversi and Othello wherein the second player\'s
          second move may or must flip one of the opposite-colored disks (as variants closest to
          the normal games).
          </p>

          <p>
          For the specific game of <b>Othello</b> (as technically differing from the historical Reversi),
          the rules state that <b>the game begins with four disks placed in a square in the middle of
          the grid, two facing white side up, two pieces with the dark side up, with same-colored
          disks on a diagonal with each other</b>. Convention has initial board position such that the
          disks with dark side up are to the north-east and south-west (from both players\'
          perspectives), though this is only marginally meaningful to play (where opening
          memorization is an issue, some players may benefit from consistency on this). If
          the disks with dark side up are to the north-west and south-east, the board may be
          rotated by 90° clockwise or counterclockwise. <b>The dark player moves first</b>.
          </p>

          <p>
          Dark must place a piece with the dark side up on the board, in such a position that there
          <b>exists at least one straight (horizontal, vertical, or diagonal) occupied line between the
           new piece and another dark piece, with one or more contiguous light pieces between them</b>.
          </p>

           <p>
           After placing the piece, dark turns over (flips, captures) all light pieces lying on a
           straight line between the new piece and any anchoring dark pieces. All reversed pieces
           now show the dark side, and dark can use them in later moves—unless light has reversed
           them back in the meantime. In other words, <b>a valid move is one where at least one piece
           is reversed</b>.
           </p>

           <p>
           Afterwards,  light plays. This player operates under the same rules, with the roles reversed:
           light lays down a light piece, causing at <b>least a dark piece to flip</b>.
           </p>

           <p>
           <b>Players take alternate turns. If one player can not make a valid move, play passes back
           to the other player. When neither player can move, the game ends. This occurs when the
           grid has filled up or when neither player can legally place a piece in any of the
           remaining squares. This means the game may end before the grid is completely filled.</b>
           This possibility may occur because one player has no pieces remaining on the board in
           that player\'s color. In over-the-board play this is generally scored as if the board
           were full (64–0).
           </p>

           <p>
           <b>The player with the most pieces on the board at the end of the game wins</b>. An exception
           to this is that if a clock is employed then if one player defaults on time that player\'s
           opponent wins regardless of the board configuration, with varying methods to determine
           the official score where one is required.
           </p></br>
           <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reversi">More Information</a>


    </string>

        ]]>

    </string>

</resources>
